# Nanette Julius

Email: njulius89@gmail.com | Cell: (661) 993-7831 https://github.com/njulius89 | www.nanettejulius.com https://linkedin.com/in/nanette-julius/

#### **SUMMARY**

Creative problem-solving web developer with the coordinating and interpersonal skills to match. I create user friendly, visually appealing applications that are functional and organized. Strong detail, communication and leadership skills developed through teaching experience. Bilingual, fluent in both English and Arabic.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Sass, Gulp, React, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, Responsive Design, Handlebars, JSON, RESTful API, AJAX, Photoshop, WordPress, Shopify, eCommerce, SEO, Google Analytics, Chrome Dev Tools, GIT, GitHub, Node, Express, mySQL & MongoDB.

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

## liveSity - Los Angeles, CA Front End Developer

09/2017 to Present

- Web developer developing in the MERN stack.
- Developing new client side scripting features
- Helping with various bug fixes and code improvements on front/back end
- Technologies leveraged: React, Node, Mongo, Express, ES6, JSX

## UCLA Coding Bootcamp - Los Angeles, CA Teaching Assistant

10/2017 to 01/2018

- Assist lead-instructor in teaching students and offered help debugging and refactoring their code
- Give solutions to advanced algorithm problems to help students think critically about problems and time complexity
- Counsel students on areas including DOM manipulation and a variety of coding languages and softwares.

#### **REX IT Inc.** – Pasadena, CA

02/2016 to 09/2017

## Jr. Front End Developer

- Designed clean, user-friendly, responsive websites/web applications
- Ensured the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
- Developed new user-facing features
- Application testing and improving test coverage

#### Freelance - Remote

07/2015 to Present

## Web Developer

- Designing websites/ web applications for clients
- Various projects using Wordpress as well as websites built from scratch
- Using HTML/CSS and Javascript based coding as well as SEO

# Nanette Julius

- Page 2-

#### **EDUCATION**

University of California Los Angeles

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

California State University of Los Angeles

B.A. Music

2017

#### APPLICATIONS BUILT

### **EventStay**

- A front end app routing users to hotels near their desired events. Users can choose an event anywhere in the world and find the cheapest, highest rated hotels near it.
- <a href="http://nanettejulius.com/EventStay">http://nanettejulius.com/EventStay</a>
- Position: Front End Developer

### Swapr

- Full stack app for trading goods with other users nearby. Users can search for items within a set distance and arrange to meet and trade using the integrated chat feature.
- <a href="https://github.com/njulius89/swapr/blob/master/README.md">https://github.com/njulius89/swapr/blob/master/README.md</a> (walk-thru of app)
- <a href="https://swapr-app.herokuapp.com">https://swapr-app.herokuapp.com</a>
- Position: Full Stack Developer focusing on Front-End

## Jamify

- Full Stack spotify clone app. Users can sign up for a personal accounts and listen to music from their favorite artists as well as save playlists.
- https://github.com/njulius89/Jamify
- Position: Sole Developer